meditation number five refers to Sangha
jewel
we finished Buddha jaw this morning we
talked about Buddha jaw we finished our
module Dharma jewel means understand the
pen is Dharma jewel very simple
understand the second husband is damaged
or if you think about the second husband
when someone gets mad at you
you have taken refuge and you're a
Buddhist okay there now there's one more
refuge which is Sangha jewel okay
so what's a Sangha jewel it's people who
understand the pen it's the community so
real the real division in in this world
is not between ordained people and non
ordained people it's not that people who
wear Rev robes are Sangha stop talking
back there it's not the case that people
who wear red robes are the real Sangha
and the rest of us are not Sangha that's
that's not the real division the real
division is who understands the pen and
who doesn't understand the pen who
understands the second husband and who
doesn't understand the second husband
people understand the pen people
understand the second husband they
automatically become a community in the
world okay whether they're from
Guangzhou or Jaipur I don't know Indus
River Valley or or mantra wolf
Jerome lives in the only town in the
world that sounds like a Smith and it
doesn't matter where you're from okay if
you understand the pin you're part of
that Club and if you don't understand
the pen you're not part of that Club
okay so Sangha means people with eyes
okay that's the meaning of meditation
number five
meditation number five is called a
person with eyes and heart heart means
they care about you they love you they
want you to come live in this town
called Sangha okay they want you to be
part of that town so they run around the
world repeating over and over the pen
every time they get a chance that's
right
that has to pass for me okay one more
time
what's this pig yeah okay if a dog come
in here and taking it in our goal they
see it as a chew toy
okay who's right the human or the done
yeah why they can use it now they can
use it it's okay dog can't you enjoy
human says why are you chewing on my pen
dog says why don't you enjoy to you okay
it's equal okay
then if I put it here all the people go
out all the dogs are out at that time
it's a pen or two toys nothing yet okay
then if the dog comes back first it
becomes a chew toy if the human
comebacks press it becomes a pen
therefore the pen is coming from my mind
not from the pen okay there's something
from my mind okay
what there's a seed opening in my mind
okay who put the seed there
yeah only I can put a seed in my mind
okay how I shared a pen with somebody
yeah okay or I shared my tutorial
somewhere
okay then I put a seed in my mind then
when I look at this thing
pen sheet opens in my mind small picture
comes out it becomes a pen okay
now and then the four steps I can get
anything I want with the four steps
there's a guide named there's a company
called spiritual gangster they make yoga
clothes they started with two people
near here in Phoenix just a man and his
wife and they started with nothing
nothing recently they were interviewed
on the morning good morning show or
whatever I never I don't have a TV for
half an hour a free free interview on
the most important morning show in the
United States half an hour they
explained why they're now the most
successful yoga clothing company and
they said it's this thing called the
four steps and they explained it on
American television the whole country
you know for half an hour they gave them
a half hour which is usually the
interview there's three minutes four
minutes they talked for half an hour
then he came back I had dinner with them
I said congratulations you know that's
amazing that they said guess why
wouldn't they what you told us to do and
then he says can I can I ask you a
personal because I said yeah and he says
how come your students don't do it
I said I don't know okay okay
he actually chided and he runs his
company that way and he only uses the
four steps and they got very famous now
and they're doing really big they got
bigger they're in bloomingdales now and
big big company now so it it's exciting
heart means share it with other people
do it yourself share it with other
people
okay you have eyes which is your
knowledge of the pin and then share it
with other people I can't get I'll have
to get the dog to get the other one okay
all right so meditation number five
think about Sangha I want to be Sangha
what Sangha jewel okay I'll tell you
something cool if you understand
emptiness
okay I mean up until recently Buddhism
was the biggest religion in the world
there were more Buddhists than anything
else okay if China is Buddhist it's the
biggest religion in the world it's 1.4
billion people you know we got Erin else
out number okay so up until now I mean
pretty much it's the biggest religion in
the world one point four billion people
minimum right something like that don't
count the American Buddhists okay one
point four billion people they were
mostly historically they are Buddhist
okay then
every morning they're supposed to get up
and go normal blue diet normal done Maya
and non-muslim they're supposed to take
refuge right i you know sang gala
capsules your children kept it to you
kendama kept secure buddhist everywhere
are praying every morning to the three
jewels okay now I'll tell you something
cool if you understand the Pens
they are praying to you that's cool
right 1 billion people
asking you for help every morning okay
then you are gonna yes I'm the jewel
okay so anyway that's time to go so
during this meditation think about whose
song the jewel think about us and the
jewel
okay think about being the person who
protects other people by teaching them
about the second husband that protects
you from unhappiness okay so you are
some dad you'll think about it spend
some time on it okay be be happy be
proud okay by accident you heard about
the pen then suddenly you got to be a
very VIP Dharma VIP you know now you're
like very special person because you can
really help people okay you teach people
the four steps you're like I don't know
it's like you're creating a world you
know a whole planet you see if you teach
anybody the four steps and if they like
this guy if you ask in that guy's name
is Ian if you ask him why you're a
Buddhist I think you say no but but he's
he took refuge he's using the first
death and it worked for him then it's
cool okay then you're Sangha jewel and
think about it and I think it's great
that we call the New York center three
jewels it's cool we even gotta the web
address right because it was so long ago
and we should thank any Thomas she comes
back to Clark okay
so during meditation number five you're
going to think about how I'm the Sangha
jewel and be in this meditation you
should feel some kind of healthy pride
like James Brown said
I'm so cool I could kiss myself so just
in this meditation you're supposed to be
like yeah I'm pretty goddamn cool you
know I understand depends I can help
people I got something to share okay be
happy this meditation is 100%
narcissistic you like I'm so cool okay
all right